<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>

<xdxf lang_from="ENG" lang_to="ENG">
  <full_name>1913 Websters Dictionary (public domain), 26 example terms</full_name>

  <ar id="A0000001">
    <head><k>abdicate</k></head>
    <def>
      <pos>v.t.</pos>
      <def><dtrn>To surrender or relinquish, as sovereign power; to withdraw
    definitely from filling or exercising, as a high office, station,
    dignity; as, to abdicate the throne, the crown, the papacy.</dtrn></def>
      <def><dtrn>To renounce; to relinquish; -- said of authority, a trust, duty,
    right, etc.</dtrn></def>
    </def>
  </ar>

  <ar id="B0000001">
    <head><k>bat</k></head>
    <pos>n.</pos>
    <def><dtrn>A large stick; a club; specifically, a piece of wood with one end
  thicker or broader than the other, used in playing baseball, cricket,
  etc.</dtrn></def>
    <def><dtrn>A sheet of cotton used for filling quilts or comfortables;
  batting.</dtrn></def>
    <def><dtrn>A part of a brick with one whole end. Bat bolt (Machinery), a bolt
  barbed or jagged at its butt or tang to make it hold the more firmly.
  Knight.</dtrn></def>
  </ar>

  <ar id="C0000001">
    <head><k>Champagne</k></head>
    <pos>n.</pos>
    <def><dtrn>A light wine, of several kinds, originally made in the province
  of Champagne, in France.</dtrn></def>
  </ar>

  <ar id="D0000001">
    <head><k>drowsy</k></head>
    <pos>a.</pos>
    <def><dtrn>Inclined to drowse; heavy with sleepiness; lethargic; dozy.</dtrn></def>
    <def><dtrn>Disposing to sleep; lulling; soporific.</dtrn></def>
    <def><dtrn>Dull; stupid.</dtrn></def>
  </ar>

  <ar id="E0000001">
    <head><k>ebullient</k></head>
    <pos>a.</pos>
    <def><dtrn>Boiling up or over; hence, manifesting exhilaration or
  excitement, as of feeling; effervescing.</dtrn></def>
  </ar>

  <ar id="F0000001">
    <head><k>frostbite</k></head>
    <pos>n.</pos>
    <def><dtrn>The freezing, or effect of a freezing, of some part of the
  body, as the ears or nose.</dtrn></def>
  </ar>

  <ar id="G0000001">
    <head><k>grandmother</k></head>
    <pos>n.</pos>
    <def><dtrn>The mother of one's father or mother.</dtrn></def>
  </ar>

  <ar id="H0000001">
    <head><k>hatchway</k></head>
    <pos>n.</pos>
    <def><dtrn>A square or oblong opening in a deck or floor, affording
  passage from one deck or story to another; the entrance to a cellar.</dtrn></def>
  </ar>

  <ar id="I0000001">
    <head><k>impoverish</k></head>
    <pos>v.t.</pos>
    <def><dtrn>To make poor; to reduce to poverty or indigence; as, misfortune
  and disease impoverish families.</dtrn></def>
    <def><dtrn>To exhaust the strength, richness, or fertility of; to make
  sterile; as, to impoverish land.</dtrn></def>
  </ar>

  <ar id="J0000001">
    <head><k>jockey</k></head>
    <pos>n.</pos>
    <def><dtrn>A professional rider of horses in races.</dtrn></def>
    <def><dtrn>A dealer in horses; a horse trader.</dtrn></def>
    <def><dtrn>A cheat; one given to sharp practice in trade.</dtrn></def>
  </ar>

  <ar id="K0000001">
    <head><k>kiln</k></head>
    <pos>n.</pos>
    <def><dtrn>A large stove or oven; a furnace of brick or stone, or a heated
  chamber, for the purpose of hardening, burning, or drying anything;
  as, a kiln for baking or hardening earthen vessels; a kiln for drying
  grain, meal, lumber, etc.; a kiln for calcining limestone.</dtrn></def>
    <def><dtrn>A furnace for burning bricks; a brickkiln.</dtrn></def>
  </ar>

  <ar id="L0000001">
    <head><k>lagoon</k></head>
    <pos>n.</pos>
    <def><dtrn>A shallow sound, channel, pond, or lake, especially one into which
  the sea flows; as, the lagoons of Venice.</dtrn></def>
    <def><dtrn>A lake in a coral island, often occupying a large portion of its
  area, and usually communicating with the sea. See Atoll. Lagoon
  island, a coral island consisting of a narrow reef encircling a
  lagoon.</dtrn></def>
  </ar>

  <ar id="M0000001">
    <head><k>megalith</k></head>
    <pos>n.</pos>
    <def><dtrn>A large stone; especially, a large stone used in ancient
  building.</dtrn></def>
  </ar>

  <ar id="N0000001">
    <head><k>noble-minded</k></head>
    <pos>a.</pos>
    <def><dtrn>Having a noble mind; honorable; magnanimous.</dtrn></def>
  </ar>

  <ar id="O0000001">
    <head><k>opponent</k></head>
    <pos>n.</pos>
    <def><dtrn>One who opposes; an adversary; an antagonist; a foe.</dtrn></def>
    <def><dtrn>One who opposes in a disputation, argument, or other verbal
  controversy; specifically, one who attacks some theirs or
  proposition, in distinction from the respondent, or defendant, who
  maintains it.</dtrn></def>
  </ar>

  <ar id="P0000001">
    <head><k>panic</k></head>
    <pos>n.</pos>
    <def><dtrn>A sudden, overpowering fright; esp., a sudden and groundless
  fright; terror inspired by a trifling cause or a misapprehension of
  danger; as, the troops were seized with a panic; they fled in a
  panic.</dtrn></def>
    <def><dtrn>By extension: A sudden widespread fright or apprehension
  concerning financial affairs.</dtrn></def>
  </ar>

  <ar id="Q0000001">
    <head><k>quarterly</k></head>
    <pos>a.</pos>
    <def><dtrn>Containing, or consisting of, a fourth part; as, quarterly
  seasons.</dtrn></def>
    <def><dtrn>Recurring during, or at the end of, each quarter; as, quarterly
  payments of rent; a quarterly meeting.</dtrn></def>
  </ar>

  <ar id="R0000001">
    <head><k>refracture</k></head>
    <pos>n.</pos>
    <def><dtrn>A second breaking (as of a badly set bone) by the surgeon.</dtrn></def>
  </ar>

  <ar id="S0000001">
    <head><k>smokestack</k></head>
    <pos>n.</pos>
    <def><dtrn>A chimney; esp., a pipe serving as a chimney, as the pipe which
  carries off the smoke of a locomotive, the funnel of a steam vessel,
  etc.</dtrn></def>
  </ar>

  <ar id="T0000001">
    <head><k>tapeworm</k></head>
    <pos>n.</pos>
    <def><dtrn>Any one of numerous species of cestode worms belonging to Tænia
  and many allied genera. The body is long, flat, and composed of
  numerous segments or proglottids varying in shape, those toward the
  end of the body being much larger and longer than the anterior ones,
  and containing the fully developed sexual organs. The head is small,
  destitute of a mouth, but furnished with two or more suckers (which
  vary greatly in shape in different genera), and sometimes, also, with
  hooks for adhesion to the walls of the intestines of the animals in
  which they are parasitic. The larvæ (see Cysticercus) live in the
  flesh of various creatures, and when swallowed by another animal of
  the right species develop into the mature tapeworm in its intestine.</dtrn></def>
  </ar>

  <ar id="U0000001">
    <head><k>U-shaped</k></head>
    <pos>a.</pos>
    <def><dtrn>Having the form of the letter U; specif. (Phys. Geog.)</dtrn></def>
    <def><dtrn>of valleys, resembling a broad U in cross profile.</dtrn></def>
  </ar>

  <ar id="V0000001">
    <head><k>vaccary</k></head>
    <pos>n.</pos>
    <def><dtrn>A cow house, dairy house, or cow pasture.</dtrn></def>
  </ar>

  <ar id="W0000001">
    <head><k>wallet</k></head>
    <pos>n.</pos>
    <def><dtrn>A bag or sack for carrying about the person, as a bag for carrying
  the necessaries for a journey; a knapsack; a beggar's receptacle for
  charity; a peddler's pack.</dtrn></def>
    <def><dtrn>A pocketbook for keeping money about the person.</dtrn></def>
  </ar>

  <ar id="X0000001">
    <head><k>xenogamy</k></head>
    <pos>n.</pos>
    <def><dtrn>Cross fertilization.</dtrn></def>
  </ar>

  <ar id="Y0000001">
    <head><k>yacht</k></head>
    <pos>n.</pos>
    <def><dtrn>A light and elegantly furnished vessel, used either for private
  parties of pleasure, or as a vessel of state to convey distinguished
  persons from one place to another; a seagoing vessel used only for
  pleasure trips, racing, etc.</dtrn></def>
  </ar>

  <ar id="Z0000001">
    <head><k>zirconium</k></head>
    <pos>n.</pos>
    <def><dtrn>A rare element of the carbon-silicon group, intermediate
  between the metals and nonmetals, obtained from the mineral zircon as
  a dark sooty powder, or as a gray metallic crystalline substance.
  Symbol Zr. Atomic weight, 90.4.</dtrn></def>
  </ar>

</xdxf>